People Detection and Tracking for Smart Square Project
======================================================

May - July 2017


Author : Camille Tarsiguel, camille.tarsiguel@ensta-paristech.fr



This code was tested on Mac OSX 10.12.5 and Matlab R2017a.

INSTALLATION : 
——————————————

Nothing is needed if working on Mac.
For other types of computer, see individual codes

FOLDER STRUCTURE : 
———————————————————

codes :

main : runs the detectors and trackers —> open file to choose parameters
main_eval : runs the evaluation

convertVid2img : convert a video to images files (1 image = 1 frame)
convImg2vid : convert image files from a folder into a video
detect_people_img : work with the script_detect_people_img
detect_people : main script for detection (on videos) work with main
MOT_KLT :  Kanade-Lucas-Tomasi tracker
MOT_v2 : Kalman based tracker
MOT : Kalman based tracker with background substraction and blob analysis
MultiObjectTrackerKLT : class to convert the KLT tracker into an multiple object tracker
natsort * all these files are helpful to reorder file when calling dir in Matlab
script_detect_img : run the detect_people_img
trainCascade : train Cascade detector on Caltech Dataset
trainRCNN : train RCNN detector on Caltech Dataset
util : Some short codes that can be useful ( 1. Convert detections from txt files to table for trainingImageLabeler	2. Convert trainingImageLabeler output to txt file	3. Display one by one the detection in one frame and change the ids (for the tracking ground truth)	4. Change the number of frames of a video )



subfolders:

data : # videos from Domplatz for evaluation and display
	—> SMSQ20  % 50 frames, for evaluation

groundTruth : Contain the groundTruth for evaluation. Each file for gt is a txt file with the name of the video it refers to. Structure is like in MOT Challenge : frame , id , x , y, w , h , (conf)

Source_code : # this is the folder containing the code for the trackers and detectors
	—> ACF # Agregated channel feature detector (results from MATLAB peopleDetectorACF, no code)
	—> Cascade # Cascade Detector (results from MATLAB CascadeObjectDetector, no code)
	—> DC # Discrete continuous tracker (offline)
	—> dollar # ACF detector
	—> DPM # Deformable part model detector
	—> HOG # HOG + SVM detector (results from MATLAB PeopleDetector, no code)
	—> MDP # Markov Decision Process tracker
	—> motchallenge-devkit # evaluation
	—> motutils # some codes for DC
	—> ROT # Robust online tracker based on tracklet confidence


RUNNING :
—————————

To run the code, you only need to open main.m and set the parameters
To evaluate (other than running time) open main_eval.m and set the parameters accordingly